SHANNON CARLINE DUKES

Jr Staff Accountant/Jr Software Engineer

112 Crespi Dr. San Francisco, CA 94132 707-971-0574 mrs.knit.wit.dukes@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I have a passion for technology and gaming and all things science, but I also love numbers in general. Not only do I have experience in multiple fields, but I have recently graduated school to develop new skills and love to learn new things. I'm a friendly person who enjoys meeting new people and working with others, but above all, I want to find that forever-job that really works hard for me the way I work hard for it. I'm never afraid of a challenge and will always be excited to explore new information as it develops!

SKILLS

- Aloha systems / TSheets / CoConstruct / MS Navision / MS Business Central / IBS / Kronos / QuickBooks / Vista Viewpoint / Netsuite
- Word / Docs / Excel / Sheets / PowerPoint / Slides / Adobe Reader / Acrobat
- Outlook / Gmail / Dropbox / Drive / Slack / Notion
- Explorer / Firefox / Chrome / Safari / Edge
- Advertising / Merchandising / Event Planning
- Business Management / Coaching / Staff Development / Recruiting
- Customer Service / Reception / Data Entry / Cash Handling / Credit Reporting
- Item Journals / GL Accounting / AP / AR / Collections
- Inventory Control / Auditing / Pricing
- HTML / CSS / SQL / Javascript / Handlebars / Python / React / Azure / MongoDB / Insomnia / Node / NPM / and more...

WORK EXPERIENCE

Backbone Labs Inc, Beaverton, OR (Remote) - ACCOUNTS PAYABLE SPECIALIST / ANALYST

5/2023 to Current

- Receiving invoices from vendors and emailing for approval to process.
- Entering all bank transactions.
- Entering all sales tax transactions completed by hired tax accountants.
- Assisting with transition of Quickbooks desktop to Netsuite
- Creation of purchase orders
- Assisting with development of procedures and filing system for invoices

- Maintaining AP email inbox
- Processing check run reports and payments

The Dutra Group, San Rafael, CA - ACCOUNTS PAYABLE SPECIALIST / ANALYST -> JR. STAFF ACCOUNTANT

12/2021 to 5/2023

- Receiving invoices from vendors within my alpha and entering into Unapproved Invoice Entries for posting, review and payment processing.
- Assisting AP coworkers with processing their alpha invoices.
- Researching new SSRS reports that may be beneficial for our department.
- Assisting IT with any Finance/Purchasing department SQL issues (for example, any linking items that are no longer pulling from one report to another within Vista).
- Creating a processing guidebook for our department since it is not already in the system upon hiring.
- Working with our tax specialist on staff to ensure that tax is applied correctly on all invoices processed and Sales and Use Tax recording, preparation and filing.
- Updating AP analysis reports utilized weekly/monthly for department and company use.
- AR tasks; collections, check processing, invoicing, adding and updating vendors.
- GL accounting assistance when needed.
- Kaiser and Anthem account reconciliations.
- Assisting with audits via Vista, Blackline and Sharepoint.
- Assisting with W9 and 1099 reporting

Straus Family Creamery, Petaluma, CA - ACCOUNTS RECEIVABLES SPECIALIST 10/2019 to 12/2021

- Processing incoming check, ACH, wire and credit card payments from customers and Farmer's Market transactions into our accounting system.
- Using Business Central and Navision systems and assisting with ERP migration from Navision to Business Central.
- Working with production, orders and warehouse departments to ensure paperwork and inventory accuracy.
- Assisting with monthly inventory and processing month end reporting.
- Tracking all AR including slow payments, Farmer's Market cash transaction logs, payment plans for past due items, customer returns and general invoicing.
- Assisting with customer returns and courtesy/customer service credits.
- Customer outreach for past due items on account and payment assistance issues.
- Assessing and processing deductions on payments received with the assistance of the Sales and Marketing department.

G Family Construction Inc, San Rafael, CA - ACCOUNTING CLERK

05/2018 to 10/2019

 Managing the accounts payable and accounts receivable for all four companies controlled by G Family (G Family Inc, G Landscape LLC, G Electric LLC, G Design

- LLC) and worked with owners/operators of each company for project billing and collections as well as office manager and main controller.
- Preparing billing for G Electric and G Landscape on a regular basis, sending out all maintenance billing monthly for G Landscape.
- Answering phones for G Electric Maintaining all intercompany charges for subcontracting work between the companies, making all payments to vendors, performing bank transfers when necessary.
- Assisting in maintaining all external property files for the owners when necessary.
- Assistance with system implementation, office coordination, event planning assistance Sales tax payments and recording through QuickBooks.
- All overflow of basic office duties or admin needs.
- Matching bank feeds daily.
- Auditing all unclassified items in the chart of accounts and classing as needed, working closely with the hired CFO to maintain the chart of accounts and set up new accounts as needed.
- Assisting hired CFO with GL accounting and all GL moves necessary for the upkeep of the chart of accounts.
- Assisting in-house IT with terminal set-ups, adjustments or updates.

Chrisad Inc, San Rafael, CA - ACCOUNTING CLERK

02/2016 to 04/2018

- Checking incoming accounting emails and processing requests from sales teams.
- Preparing the payment sheet from the previous day's sales as well as the daily production report and growth report.
- Distributing invoices.
- Processing daily accounts receivables orders.
- Updating client files and processing new client agreements.
- Processing billing each month as well as collection calls on delinquent accounts.
- Closing out daily charges.
- Following up on pending items with sales teams.
- Auditing statements each month.
- Creating and sending out collection and website deactivation letters for delinquent accounts.
- Sending invoices and ledgers to clients when requested.
- Coding credit card statements for processing.
- Entering AP items directly to GL accounts.
- Matching invoices processed for clients to invoices received from vendors for verification.

Floortex Design of San Rafael, San Rafael, CA - ADMINISTRATIVE ASSISTANT

07/2015 to 03/2016

- Answering phones
- Faxing, filing, photocopying, scanning Invoicing and bookkeeping
- General cleanliness of showroom and upkeep

- Private labeling samples
- Tracking shipments and tracking projects with clients
- Checking in and checking out samples
- Merchandising of showroom tile department and beginning the setup of social media for San Rafael location
- Greeting clients and referring them accordingly to sales team members
- Collaborating with admin at alternative showroom for invoicing and client referrals
- Interacting with reps from product lines we represent
- Assisting with pricing and sales where necessary
- Pulling dropped line items from sample collections.

EDUCATION

Casa Grande High School, Petaluma, CA - General Education

09/2000 to 06/2003

Left Casa Grande early to complete high school education doing independent study so I could also work a full time job at the same time.

Valley Oaks School, Petaluma, CA - High School Diploma

09/2003 to 09/2004

Completed my high school education doing independent study and working full time.

UC Berkeley Extension, Berkeley, CA - Full Stack Coding Bootcamp

06/2021 to 11/2021

Graduated from a full stack coding bootcamp with a certificate which concluded in November 2021. Also studying in my off time using web based programs and applications including Mimo, Programming Hub and Free Code Camp.

AWARDS/PUBLIC SERVICE

- Published in the Immortal Verses Series from Powtry.com in 2006 for my poem "As I Stare"
- Served the homeless with Food Not Bombs in Santa Rosa.
- Crochet for the homeless while on public transit.
- Teach knitting and crochet.
- Received additional Certificate in Web Design from Mimo app updated 8/2023.
- Received additional Certificate in HTML from Mimo app updated 8/2023.
- Received additional Certificate in Python from Mimo app updated 8/2023.
- Received additional Certificate in Javascript from Mimo app updated 8/2023.
- Received additional Certificate in Responsive Web Design from freeCodeCamp.org.
- Received additional Certificate in Javascript Algorithms and Data Structures from freeCodeCamp.org.
- Working on creating my own app in my spare time.

LINKS

- www.linkedin.com/in/shannon-d-a9b518213
- https://github.com/ShannonDukes
- Portfolio https://shannondukes.github.io/React-Portfolio/